Inventory of the Peace subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Peace subject collection
1891-2005
XX761
Hoover Institution Archives
17 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 4 compact sound cassettes (11.7 linear feet)
Pamphlets, clippings, leaflets, letters, memoranda, circulars, reports, and bulletins, relating to pacifism, disarmament, international law, the Paris Peace Conference of 1919, the League of Nations and other actual or proposed international organizations, and various proposed plans to ensure peace.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. Use copies of all sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
League of Nations miscellany, Hoover Institution Archives
Herbert Hoover, the League of Nations and the World Court: typescript, Hoover Institution Archives
Christian Archibald Herter papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Malbone W. Graham papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Aleksandr Nikolaevich Krupenskiĭ papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection relates to pacifism, disarmament, international law, the Paris Peace Conference of 1919, the League of Nations and other actual or proposed international organizations, and various proposed plans to ensure peace. It consists of pamphlets, bulletins, leaflets, clippings, letters, memoranda, reports, circulars, scrapbooks, and audio recordings.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series: Printed matter; Incremental material; Scrapbooks; and Sound recordings.
League of Nations.; Paris Peace Conference (1919-1920); Disarmament.; International law.; International organization.; Pacifism.; Peace.; Phonotapes.; World War, 1914-1918--Peace.
- PRINTED MATTER, 1881-1939; 1-14 (Box 1-14)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains pamphlets, brochures, booklets, and bulletins, mainly in French and German
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by author or by the title when author is unspecified, and chronologically thereunder
  - Académie de Droit International de la Haye, Cours de 1933, rapport du curatorium (Folder 1: 1)
  - "Almanach de la paix,", 1909 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Alvarez, Alejandro, Et la Codification du Droit International Américain, 1913 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Anzilotti, Dionisio, Sugli effetti dell'inadempienza di obbligazioni internazionali aventi per oggetto una soma di dinaro, circa 1910 (Folder 1: 4)
  - L'Arbitrage entre Nations, Revue mensuelle, 1900 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Arndt, Adolf, Schifffahrtsabgaben auf Rhein und Elbe nach Völkerrcht, 1929 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Les Atrocités Bulgares, Un Appel au Monde Civilisé, 1913 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Baer, Ulbert, Der Kriegszustand, 1915 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Balch, Thomas Willing, Rechtliche und Politische Fragen zwischen Nationen, 1923 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Baldoni, Claudio, 1931-1932
    - La zona di Tangeri nel diritto internazionale e nel diritto marocchino, 1931 (Folder 1: 10)
    - La successione nel tempo delle norme diritto internazionale private, 1932 (Folder 1: 10)
  - Balogh, Elemér, The Traditional Element in Grotius' Conception of International Law, 1929 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Bar, Ludwig Von, 1900-1913
    - Der Burenkrieg, die Russifizierung Finnlands und die Haager Friedenskonferenz, 1900 (Folder 1: 12)
    - Gutachten über die Frage der Einrichtung eines ständigen international. Gerichtshofs für Klagen von Privatpersonen gegen fremde Staaten, 1913 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Barrett, John, The Pan American Outlook: A Survey, 1919 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Der Basler Reparationsbericht, Das Gutachten des Beneduce-Ausschusses, 1932 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Baty, Thomas, 1928-1931
    - The Three-Mile Limit, 1928 (Folder 1: 15)
    - Prize Law and Modern Condition, 1931 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Baumgarten, A., Das Wesen des Volkerrechts, 1928 (Folder 1: 16)
  - Becker, Paul, Der völkerrechtliche Schutz des menschlichen Lebens auf hoher See, 1929 (Folder 1: 17)
  - Beer, Ludwig, Sonderabdruck aus Niemeyers Zeitschrift fur Internationales Recht, Bd. XXV, 1929 (Folder 1: 18)
  - Beichmann, F.V.N., 1920-1929
    - Le Pacte de la Société des Nations dans le Traité de Paix de Versailles, 1920 (Folder 1: 19)
    - L'établissement d'un Tribunal International Permanent, 1929 (Folder 1: 19)
  - Berendts, Eduard, über Grenzmarkenpolitik und die finnländische Frage insbesondere: Rede gehalten am 14. Januar 1907 (Folder 1: 20)
  - Bern, Kanton, Rechtsgutachten über die Grenzverhaltnisse am Doubs zwischen Frankreich, 1909 (Folder 1: 21)
  - Bertha von Suttner, Der Frauenweltbund und der Krieg, 1905 (Folder 1: 22)
  - Besehwerden der Saarbevölkerung über das bisherige Völkerbundsregime, 1929 (Folder 1: 23)
  - Bjï¿½rnson, Bjï¿½rnstjerne, Fred! Oratorium, 1892 (Folder 1: 24)
  - Borchardt, Edwin M., 1910-1924
    - The Limitation of Protection by Contract Between the Citizen and Foreign Government or by Municipal Legislation, 1910 (Folder 1: 25)
    - Enemy Private Property, 1924 (Folder 1: 25)
  - Bornhak, Conrad, Russland und Finnland, ein Beitrag zu der Lehre von den Staatenverbindungen, 1909 (Folder 1: 26)
  - Boyd, Jorge E., La République de Panama et le droit international, 1911 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Brandes, Georg and Otto Borngräber, Appel ï¿½ la paix, Manifestes publiés par la conférence des neutres, 1916 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Brennwald, G., Luft and Recht, 1910 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Brie, Siegfried, Die Fortschritte des Völkerrechts seit dem Wiener Congress: Rede bei Antritt des Rektorats der Universität Breslau, 1890 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Bruns, Viktor, 1931-1936
    - Régime douanier entre l'Allemagne et l'Autriche: exposé écrit du gouvernement allemand: observations, plaidoirie, réplique de M. le professeur Viktor Bruns (Folder 2: 5)
    - Völkerrecht als Rechtsordnung I, 1936 (Folder 2: 5)
  - "Bulletin de la Ligue des catholiques franï¿½ais pour la paix,", 1911-1913 (Folder 2: 6)
  - "Bulletin of the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom,", 1922-1923 (Folder 2: 7)
  - "Bulletin Officiel Du IVme Congrès Universel De La Paix,", 1895 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Burckhardt, Walther, 1923
    - Die Völkerrechtliche Verantwortlichkeit der Staaten, 1923 (Folder 2: 9)
    - Die Unvollkommenheit des Völkerrechts, 1923 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Bureau International de la Paix, 1907-1928
    - Liste des organes du mouvement pacifiste, 1907 (Folder 2: 10)
    - Leaflets, 1923-1925 (Folder 2: 10)
    - XXVIE Congrès Universel de la Paix, 1928 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1931-1932
    - Government and Liberty, 1931 (Folder 2: 11)
    - The World Waits on Politics, 1932 (Folder 2: 11)
  - Butte, George Charles, Amerikanische Prisengerichtsbarkeit, 1913 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Butz, Gustav, Die Bekämpfung des Mädchenhandels im internationalen Rechte, 1908 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Carnegie, Andrew, 1906-1909
    - Für das internationale Schiedsgericht: Rektoratsrede an die Studierenden der schottischen Universität St. Andrews, 1906 (Folder 2: 14)
    - Amerika gegen die Rüstungen von Andrew Carnegie, Nicholas Murray Butler, Charles E. Jefferson, 1909 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Cavaglieri, Arrigo, 1921-1929
    - Belligeranza, neutralitaè posizioni giuridiche intermedie, 1921 (Folder 2: 15)
    - La natura giuridica dei tribunali di Rodi, 1921 (Folder 2: 15)
    - La natura giuridica della corte internazionale delle prede, 1929 (Folder 2: 15)
    - Note critiche su la teoria dei mezzi coercitivi al difuori della guerra, 1929 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Central Organization for a Durable Peace, International Congress for the Study of the Principles of a Durable Peace, Berne, 1916
    - Concepted Action, by Holt Hamilton (Folder 2: 16)
    - The Peaceful Settlement of International Disputes, Two Difficulties and Two Suggestions, by J. T. Lawrence (Folder 2: 16)
  - Chambre des Députés, Admission du Grand-Duché de Luxemburg dans la Société des Nations, 1920 (Folder 2: 17)
  - Combothecra, Xénocrate Spiridon, 1917
    - La Grèce indépendante, 1917 (Folder 3: 1)
    - Trois pays garantis: Belgique, Grèce, Suisse, 1917 (Folder 3: 1)
  - Comptes-rendus des séances de la Commission permanente belge de l'Alimentation humaine, 1912 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Congrès International de Paix ï¿½ la Haye, 1913 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Cordovani, P. M., Elementa Juris Naturalis Internationalis, 1924 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Coudert, Frederic R., Law versus Force in the Solution of International Controversies, 1931 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Cuche, Paul, Conférences de Philosophie du Droit: Le Mirage du Droit naturel. Les Postulats métaphysiques du Positivisme juridique. Réalisme et Conceptualisme juridiques. Critique du Concept de la Personnalité morale, 1920 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Dejongh, Charles, L'Allegmagne et les conventions de La Haye, pacifisme et démocratie; conférence faite ï¿½ la Maison du peuple de Lausanne, le 8 avril, 1915 (Folder 3: 7)
  - Delhorbe, Florian Marie, Essai sur le neutre, 1917 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Die deutsche Gesellschaft für Völkerrecht, Mitteilungen der Deutschen Gesellschaft für Völkerrecht, Heft 7, 1926 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Die deutsche Kundgebung zur Abrüstungskonferenz, Erklärung des Abrüstungsausschusses der Internationalen Frauenorganisationen anlässlich der Konferenz für die Herabsetzung und Begrenzung der Rüstungen, 1932 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Die deutsche Liga für Völkerbund, 1926-1932
    - Abrüstungsvorschläge der Deutschen Liga für Völkerbund, 1926 (Folder 3: 11)
    - Memorandum zur Vertrauenskrise des Völkerbundes, 1932 (Folder 3: 11)
  - Deutsche Vereinigung für Internationales Recht, Der Krieg und die Privatschuldverhältnisse, Stenographischer Bericht über die am Sonnabend, den 29. November 1913, abends 6 Uhr im Saal der Handelskammer zu Berlin abgehaltene Versammlung, 1914 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Deutscher Ausschuss für Oberschlesien, Zusammenstellung von Protokollen und Berichten über den dritten polnischen Aufstand im oberschlesischen Abstimmungsgebiet (Beginn am 3. Mai 1921) (Folder 3: 13)
  - Dickinson, Edwin D., 1929-1931
    - The Relation of British and American Prize Law to International Law and its Proper Treatment in the General Course, 1929 (Folder 3: 14)
    - Recall of Witnesses under the Walsh Act, 1931 (Folder 3: 14)
    - Changing Concepts and the Doctrine of Incorporation, 1932 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Diena, Giulio, 1911-1912
    - Les conflits de lois en matière de droits réels ï¿½ l'Institut de droit international, 1911 (Folder 3: 15)
    - Die Erwerbung Tripolitaniens durch Italien und deren völkerrechtlicher charakter, 1912 (Folder 3: 15)
  - Dirr, P., Bismarck und Belgien, 1915 (Folder 3: 16)
  - Dochow, Franz, Vereinheitlichung des Arbeiterschutzrechtes durch Staatsverträge: ein Beitrag zum internationalen Verwaltungsrecht, 1907 (Folder 3: 17)
  - Drago, Luis M., Les Emprunts d'état et leurs rapports avec la politique internationale, 1907 (Folder 3: 18)
  - Dï¿½ason, Jón, Grï¿½nlands Retsstilling i Middelalderen, 1931 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Dubois, Raphael, Nécessité et urgence de la création d'instituts pour l'étude par la methode scientifique des questions relatives au pacifisme, 1914 (Folder 3: 20)
  - Ducommun, Elie, Rapport du Bureau international de la paix sur les manifestations du 22 février 1903: [Signé et daté Berne, mai 1903] (Folder 3: 21)
  - Dupuis, Charles, Le différend Roumano-Hongrois au Conseil de la Société des Nations en septembre 1927 (Folder 3: 22)
  - Eagleton, Clyde, Progress in the Codification of the Law of the Responsibility of States, 1930 (Folder 4: 1)
  - Einige Bemerkungen zur Antwort von Professor Burckhardt, 1931 (Folder 4: 2)
  - D'Estournelles de Constant, 1906-1912
    - Die Beschränkung der Rüstungen. Bericht über die Beschränkgung, 1906 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Limitation des Charges Navales et Militaires, 1912 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Exposition de Bruxelles 1910, Les Institutions patronales de la compagnie des forges de Chatillon, Commentry et Neuves-Maisons (Folder 4: 4)
  - Faluhelyi, F., Der Pariser Kellog-Pakt und dessen Bedeutung vom Rotary-Standpunkte betrachtet, 1929 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Fehlinger, H., Erfolge der internationalen Arbeitsorganisation, 1924 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Feine, Gert, Die völkerrechtliche Stellung der Staatsschiffe, 1921 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Fleischmann, Max C., 1909-1929
    - Die Ausweisung von Reichsangehörigen aus den deutschen Schutzgebieten, 1909 (Folder 4: 8)
    - Die Mischehen in den deutschen Schutzgebieten, 1910 (Folder 4: 8)
    - Sonderabdruck aus: Zeitschrift für Völkerrecht, 1929 (Folder 4: 8)
  - La Fontaine, Henri, Essai de bibliographie de la paix, 1891 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Frank, Louis, La Paix et le district fédéral du monde, l'avenir de la Belgique au point de vue international, 1910 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Freund, Georg S., Der Schutz der Gläubiger gegenuber auswärtigen Schuldnerstaaten, insbesondere bei auswärtigen Staatsanleihen, 1910 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Frey, Emil, Die Neutralität der Schweiz. Rede gehalten von a. Bundesrath Emil Freu am 16. November 1899 in der demokratischen Vereinigung Winterthur, 1900 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Fried, Alfred H., 1900-1908
    - Die Haager Conferenz: ihre Bedeutung und ihre Ergebnisse, 1900 (Folder 4: 13-14)
    - Weder Sedan, noch Jena, 1904 (Folder 4: 13-14)
    - Die Grundlagen des revolutionären Pacifismus, 1908 (Folder 4: 13-14)
    - Der Weg zum Weltfrieden im Jahre 1910: pazifistische Chronik (Folder 4: 13-14)
    - Der Weg zum Weltfrieden im Jahre 1911: pazifistische Chronik (Folder 4: 13-14)
  - "Die Friedensbewegung," März, 1913 (Folder 4: 15)
  - Gabrys-Parsaitis, Le problème des nationalités, 1916 (Folder 4: 16)
  - Gagliardi, Ernst, Die Entstehung der schweizerischen Neutralität, 1915 (Folder 4: 17)
  - Gareis, Carl, Die Interdiction von Sklavenhandel und Seeraub, 1929 (Folder 4: 18)
  - Gerber, Hans, 1926
    - Kulturautonomie als Eigenart minderheitenrechtlicher Ordnung und ihre Verwirklichung nach der estnischen Verfassung, 1926 (Folder 4: 19)
    - Ein europäischer Bund?, 1926 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Giese, Friedrick, Zur Geltung der Reichsverfassung in den deutschen Kolonien, 1911 (Folder 4: 20)
  - Gmelin, Hans, Politische Abhängigkeit von Staaten, 1932 (Folder 4: 21)
  - Gram, G., Louis Renault et le droit international, 1918 (Folder 4: 22)
  - Grauer-Frey Isidor, Die Wiedergutmachung schweizerischer Kriegsschäden, 1929 (Folder 4: 23)
  - Great Britain Board of Education, The League of Nations and the Schools, 1932 (Folder 4: 24)
  - Gross, Leo, Der Logische Widerspruch in Pazifismus und die Anderung der Völkerbundssatzung, 1930 (Folder 4: 25)
  - Guggenheim, Paul, La Convention Germano-Suisse du 15 juillet 1931 en vue d'éviter la double imposition, 1932 (Folder 5: 1)
  - Hagens, Luitpold, Staat, Recht und Völkerrecht, 1890 (Folder 5: 2)
  - Haden, L. W., Microphotography in the International Labor Office Library, 1939 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Hazard, Henry B., 1926-1932
    - International Problems in Respect to Nationality by Naturalization and of Married Women, 1926 (Folder 5: 4)
    - The Right of Appeal in Naturalization Cases in the Federal Courts, 1927 (Folder 5: 4)
    - Restrictions ethniques ï¿½ la naturalisation et ï¿½ l'acquisition de la qualité de citoyen aux états-Unis d'Amérique, 1932 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Hermans, Herrn W., Versailles, 1931 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Hilty, Karl, Der ewige Friede, seine Wünschbarkeit und Möglichkeit, 1890 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Hobson, John Atkinson, The Open Door, 1916 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Hobza, Antonie, La Petite Entente, 1933 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Hoffman, H. Edler, La Colonie, le Protectorat at les Protectorats Allemands et Anglais sur le Continent Africain, 1909 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Hold v. Ferneck, Alexander Freih, 1909-1929 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Hrabar, Vladimir, La Doctrine de Droit International chez Saint-Augustin, 1932 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Huber, Max, 1908-1916
    - Die Gleichheit der Staaten, 1908 (Folder 5: 12)
    - Gemeinschafts- und Sonderrecht unter Staaten, 1916 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Hübler, Bernhard, Die Magistraturen des völkerrechtlichen Verkehrs (Gesandtschafts- und Konsularrecht) und die Exterritorialität: zum Gebrauch für Vorlesungen über Völkerrecht und Politik, 1900 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Hudson, Manley O., The Duration of the War between the United States and Germany, 1926 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Imberg, Kurt Edward, Schiedsgerichtsvertrage der Vereinigten Staaten von Nordamerika bis zur ersten Haager Friedenskonferenz, 1899 (Folder 5: 15)
  - Institut de Droit International sessions, 1927-1932 (Folder 5: 16)
  - International Federation of League of Nation Societies, XVth Plenary Congress, 1931 (Folder 5: 17)
  - Jahrreiss, Hermann, Völkerbunds-Mitgliedschaft und Reichsverfassung: Leipziger Antrittsvorlesung, 1926 (Folder 5: 18)
  - Jessup, Philip C., The Palmas Island Arbitration, 1928 (Folder 5: 19)
  - Kaas, Ludwig, Commission de Constatation et de Conciliation, 1929 (Folder 5: 20)
  - Kalischek, Walter, Der Papst und das Völkerrecht, 1918 (Folder 5: 21)
  - Kamarowsky, Leonid A., über die Friedensbestrebungen der Völker. Die Abrüstungsfrage. über einige internationale Kongresse im Jahre 1889: drei Abhandlungen (Folder 5: 22)
  - Kampffmeyer, George, Die Irreleitung der offentlichen Meinung in der Mannesmann-Angelegenheit, 1910 (Folder 5: 23)
  - Kapras, John, The Peace League of George Poděbrad, King of Bohemia, 1919 (Folder 5: 24)
  - Kaufmann, Erich, Studien zum Liquidationsrecht, 1925 (Folder 6: 1)
  - Kayser, Wilhelm, Rousseau, Kant, Herder über den ewigen Frieden, 1916 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Kernfragen des Abrüstungsproblems und die Aufrüstung Frankreichs und seiner militärischen Vasallen, 1929 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Klein, Peter, 1914-1915
    - Internationale Gerichtsbarkeit für das Gebiet des Weltwechselrechts, 1914 (Folder 6: 4)
    - Studien zum interlokalen Privatrecht, 1915 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Knubben, Ron, Wörterbuch des Völkerrechts und der Diplomatie, 1928 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Kohler, Josef, 1918-1919
    - Zeitschrift für Vergleichende, 1919 (Folder 6: 6)
    - Das Urteil des gemischten Appellationsgerichts in Alexandrien vom 26. Juni 1917, 1918 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Kolben, Max, Der Aussichtsreichste Schritt zur Beschrankung der Seerustungs-Ausgaben, 1929 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Komitees für die Wiedergutmachung schweizerischer Kreigsschäden, Die Kreigsschäden im Nationalrat, 1929 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Körling, Heinrich, Die Rechtsnatur des Völkerbundes eine rechtswissenschaftliche Untersuchung, 1922 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Korselt, Theodor, Die völkerrechtliche Handlungsfähigkeit der deutschen Einzelstaaten in Vergangenheit und Gegenwart, 1917 (Folder 6: 10)
  - Köstler, Rudolf, Die religionspolitischen Bestimmungen des Friedensvertrages, 1921 (Folder 6: 11)
  - Kraus, Herbert, 1925-1930
    - Zur Frage des Eintritts Deutschlands in den Völkerbund, 1925 (Folder 6: 12)
    - Das Problem internationaler sittlicher Ordnung bei Immanuel Kant: Rede anlässlich der Verfassungsfeier der Georg-August-Universität zu Göttingen am 20. Juli 1930 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Kuhn, Edgar, Der Missbrauch des Roten Kreuzes. Eine kritisch-dogmatische Studie, 1905 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Kunz, Joseph L., 1927-1932
    - Zur Hypothesis von Primat des Völkerrechts, 1927 (Folder 6: 14)
    - Une nouvelle théorie de l'état fédéral, 1931 (Folder 6: 14)
    - Die Abrüstungskonferenz des Völkerbundes, 1932 (Folder 6: 14)
  - Lambert, Henri, Le seul règlement possible de la situation internationale, la solution libre-échangiste, circa 1932 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Lammasch, Heinrich, 1905-1915
    - Katholizismus und Völkerrecht, circa 1905 (Folder 6: 16)
    - Internationale Schiedsgerichtsbarkeit, 1909 (Folder 6: 16)
    - über isolierte und institutionelle Schiedsgerichte, 1912 (Folder 6: 16)
    - Die Fortbildung der internationalen Schiedsgerichtsbarkeit, 1914 (Folder 6: 16)
    - Rückblicke auf die Haager Friedenskonferenzen, circa 1915 (Folder 6: 16)
  - Lange, Christian L., Die Bedingungen eines dauernden Friedens: Bericht über die Arbeiten der Union, 1917 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Langhans-Ratzeburg, Manfred, 1925-1928
    - Karte des Selbstbestimmungsrechtes der Völker, 1925 (Folder 7: 1)
    - Herrschaftsverteilung und Herrschaftsformen auf der Erde 1914 und 1927 (Folder 7: 1)
    - Neue politische Karten der Erdteile auf staats-und völkerrechtliche Grundlage, 1928 (Folder 7: 1)
  - Lapradelle, Albert, 1924-1930
    - La loi polonaise de 1920 sur la nationalité et les traités de Versailles, 1924 (Folder 7: 2)
    - Les Suisses et les dommages de guerre, 1930 (Folder 7: 2)
  - Laun, Rudolf, 1917-1930
    - Angriff und Verteidigung: eine völkerrechtliche Formel im dienste eines dauernden Friedens, 1917 (Folder 7: 3)
    - L'Autonomia del diritto, 1930 (Folder 7: 3)
  - League of Nations, Secretariat, Information Section, 1923-1930
    - Der ständige internationale Gerichtshof, 1923 (Folder 7: 4-5)
    - Der Völkerbund und der Schutz der Minderheiten, 1923 (Folder 7: 4-5)
    - Die Satzung des Völkerbundes, 1926 (Folder 7: 4-5)
    - Die Satzung des Völkerbundes, circa 1930 (Folder 7: 4-5)
  - League of Nations Union, Annual Report for 1931 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Lee, R.W., Hugo Grotius, Annual Lecture on a Master Mind. Henriette Hertz Frust of the British Academy, 1930 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Leibholz, Gerhard, Das Verbot der Willkür und des Ermessensmissbrauches im völkerrechtlichen Verkehr der Staaten, 1929 (Folder 7: 8)
  - Lenz, Adolf, Die Ansprüche an die feindlichen Staaten aus deren Völkerrechtswidrigkeiten, 1915 (Folder 7: 9)
  - Levy, J. A., Wet of tractaat? Bijdrage tot de leer der internationale rechtseenheid, 1880 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Lichtervelde, Louis, Heures d'histoire: le 4 aoï¿½t 1914 au Parlement belge, 1918 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Lie, Mikael H., Luxemburg eller Belgien, 1915 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Liepmann, Moritz, Nach welchen Gesichtspunkten ist für Zwecke des Seebeuterrechts die feindliche oder neutrale Eigenschaft der Ware zu bestimmen? Ein Reformvorschlag, circa 1907 (Folder 7: 13)
  - Ligue pour la révision du traité de Trianon, Faits, 1928 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Lingg, Emil, Das Rechtsproblem des Völkerbundes: Empirische Studien, 1930 (Folder 7: 15)
  - Un livre noir: correspondance télégraphique entre les Souvenains déchus de Grèce et Berlin, 1915 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Loening, Edgar, Separat-Abdruck aus dem Handwörterbuch der Staatswissenschaften, 1910 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Loewenthal, Eduard, Grundzüge zur Reform und Kodifikation des Völkerrechts, 1912 (Folder 7: 18)
  - Loutsch, Hubert, Pour la patrie: le Grand-Duché de Luxembourg: son passé historique, sa situation internationale et économique d'aprés les traités, 1919 (Folder 7: 19)
  - Lundborg, Ragnar, Die gegenwärtigen Staatenverbindungen: eine staatsrechtliche und völkerrechtliche Untersuchung, 1921 (Folder 8: 1)
  - Luxburg, Guido, Das internationale Privatrecht des ehelichen Güterrechts nach dem bürgerlichen Gesetzbuch für das deutsche Reich, 1912 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Mahaim, Ernest, Les conflits des lois en matière de domicile civil ï¿½ I'Institut de Droit International, 1931 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Manes, Alfred, Sozialpolitik in den Friedensverträgen und im Völkerbund, 1919 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Manigk, Alfred, Die Idee des Naturrechts, 1926 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Martin, Charles, 1930-1931
    - The Foreign Policies of the United States, 1930 (Folder 8: 6)
    - The United States of Europe, 1930 (Folder 8: 6)
    - Institutions and Progress for the Advancement of International Peace: an Evaluation, 1931 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Martin, William and Ernest Bovet, Dix ans de Société des Nations: 1920-1930 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Martitz, Ferdinand, 1907-1919